<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Web & Portfolio frandev]]></title><description><![CDATA[My personal website containing a porftolio and blog, where I can share my projects and experiences about technology]]></description><link>https://frandev.me</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 10:53:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[My experience with Pop!_OS after 10 months]]></title><description><![CDATA[For a lots of months, I struggled finding a linux distribution that was stable enough and appeal to me. After trying Ubuntu, Linux Mint, KDE…]]></description><link>https://frandev.me/my-experience-with-pop-os/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://frandev.me/my-experience-with-pop-os/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 20:16:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;For a lots of months, I struggled finding a linux distribution that was stable enough and appeal to me. After trying Ubuntu, Linux Mint, KDE Neon and Manjaro, I decided to install Pop!_OS, a Ubuntu-based distribution but featuring a custom GNOME desktop created by System76.
At the beginning I though that it will be just Ubuntu with a few modifications, but at the end it has been more than that and you can see it just when you download it, because unlike Ubuntu you can choose between two different iso files, one with AMD drivers and another one with NVIDIA drivers installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The installation process is very smooth like the great majority of linux distributions. The default desktop enviroment as I mentioned before comes with GNOME but with a few differences in icons, theme, color scheme and extensions.
Pop!_OS has Flatpak installed and Flathub configured by default and the Pop!_Shop can be used to install fratpaks aswell which is something that I really like.
Another thing that I like is the auto-tiling, that it can be use for navigation and management of windows fully through the keyboard, it comes with a really sane shortcuts configuration, that complements very well with workspaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main uses cases are in the first place software development and secondary gaming, I haven’t had any problem with either of them (apart from poor linux-games support) but take into acount that software development on linux is a very efficient workplace,
and that I’m just a casual gamer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general I have found a stable and customizable distribution that I recommend to anyone who uses it the same way as me, of course you have to feel comfortable with GNOME. But I have to say that the auto-tiling and keyboard control has opened an new opportunity to test tiling WMs, maybe with another distribution, who knows…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally if you are interested you can download it from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pop.system76.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and if you want to see some of the repositories of the project you can visit this &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pop-os&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.S. Still learning and improving my english :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>